# KANAV SHARMA

## Data Scientist

## CONTACT

9469850599 kanav608@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/kanavsharma-896b1021b/

# EDUCATION

SURESH GYAN VIHAR UNIVERSITY, JAIPUR

BTech CSE 7.9 CGPA **2015-2019** 

#### SKILLS

**Programming Languages:** R, Python **Software:** 

Gitlab, Docker, SQL, R Studio,
Spyder, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau,
AWS **Tools:** 

Sklearn, Pandas, NumPy, Selenium, Scipy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, R-libraries

#### SUMMARY

An experienced Data Scientist with more than 5 years experience .I have hands on experience in analyzing & interpreting data with good numerical accuracy. I believe I have the ability to juggle an array of tasks whilst staying focused on priorities.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### SENIOR ANALYST

Transunion CIBIL Pvt Ltd

March 2023 - Present

- Implemented automated analysis processes shared with the sales team,
   resulting in a remarkable 1/15 reduction in team workload for file generation.
- Boosted a banking sector model's accuracy from 13% to 28%, implementing impactful enhancements for enhanced predictive capabilities.

#### JUNIOR ASSOCIATE

Kreate Technologies Pvt Ltd

Feb 2020 - March 2023

- Responsible for growing business in power sector up to 300% in 2 years by using different statistical techniques, dealing with time series data.
- Reduction of MAPE by 40% by creating ensemble model out of best models from existing models like tree based, boosting models
- Reduction of MAPE by 35% for existing clients by extracting pixel values from images using selenium(Python)
- Reduction of MAPE by 22% by using Multiple linear regression.
- Prepared accuracy report on a regular interval of time using Tableau.
- Use AWS services like EC2, S3, SageMaker for increasing productivity.

#### DATA SCIENTIST

RoboMQ Pvt Ltd

Jan 2019- Jan 2020

- Predict favorable condition for a Tennis match using Decision Tree
   (Classification) with ID3 algorithm. Accuracy Score: 0.84
- Assessed the chances of a user going to access the Contact Us link through certain links in the website using Logistic Regression

(Classification). Accuracy Score: 0.86

#### ACADEMIC PROJECT

Crime Management System

• An integrated system using **PHP & SQL** where all crimes and investigations can be created, read, updated and deleted using valid credentials.

Restaurant Management System

 A GUI was built using Python and has upgraded GST rates. The GUI helps users to create, update details on the billing system of restaurants. Tkinter is used in this project